<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jason</title>
    <description>Jason Willems&#39; Blog</description>  
    <link>www.jasonwillems.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="www.jasonwillems.com//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Apple And Samsung: A Recent History Of Advertising</title>
      <description>
        
          &lt;h1&gt;Apple And Samsung: A Recent History Of Advertising&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;br&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;subheading&quot;&gt;
	&lt;div id=&quot;blogdatestamp&quot; style=&quot;font-weight:bold;font-family:times;text-align:center;&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;22 Feb 2014&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;div id=&quot;blogtext&quot;&gt;
		2013 has been labeled by many as the lost year in tech, devoid of any disruptive new product categories. The main media focus was on lobbying for tax laws, mergers, acquisitions, and IPOs (and even floating offshore tax havens). It&amp;rsquo;s hard to argue any of these did much for the industry from a consumer perspective, but it&amp;rsquo;s easy to overlook other important aspects of this industry.&lt;br /&gt;
		&lt;br /&gt;
		Advertising, in particular, is has been changing a lot. Advertising by tech companies has quickly evolved over the last few years, and competitors have increasingly influenced and responded to each other through their campaigns.&lt;br /&gt;
		&lt;br /&gt;
		As far back as I know, impactful advertising in this industry began with a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2zfqw8nhUwA&quot;&gt;1984 Super Bowl commercial&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s important to understand the context of this commercial, in order to appreciate it fully. This was at a time when Apple&amp;rsquo;s fiercest competition was IBM who was at the time selling mainframe computers. Apple, meanwhile, was trying to commoditise the home computer. They chose to portray rigid mainframe computers, sold mostly to governments and large organizations, as inflexible and unattainable to the masses, while they were meanwhile empowering people. The 1984 big brother analogy was a powerful one.&lt;br /&gt;
		
        
      </description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <link>www.jasonwillems.com//2014/02/22/Apple-and-Samsung-Recent-History-of-Advertising/</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">www.jasonwillems.com//2014/02/22/Apple-and-Samsung-Recent-History-of-Advertising/</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 21st Century Analogue to the Second Amendment</title>
      <description>
        
          &lt;h1&gt;The 21st Century Analogue to the Second Amendment&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;br&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;subheading&quot;&gt;
	&lt;div id=&quot;blogdatestamp&quot; style=&quot;font-weight:bold;font-family:times;text-align:center;&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;16 Nov 2013&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;div id=&quot;blogtext&quot;&gt;

		Typically, I keep my distance from such polarised issues, since it only stands to encourage the incalculable amount of time spent deliberating comparatively trivial issues. However, in this case I think it&amp;rsquo;s worth putting the Second Amendment into its proper context. &lt;br /&gt;
		&lt;br /&gt;
		If you think its primary focus is about preserving or restricting the right to a cellar full of guns, as I fear most people do, then sadly you&amp;rsquo;re missing the point entirely.&lt;br /&gt;
		&lt;br /&gt;
		At its time of inception, the Second Amendment was about securing a balance of power between the government and its citizens. Historically - with many examples today - governments that have been able to mandate a great power imbalance in their favour, have have tended towards violence and oppression rather than safety and liberty.&lt;br /&gt;
		&lt;br /&gt;
		In this sense, today&amp;rsquo;s debate over the Second Amendment should have nothing to do with guns; the debate should be about its principle: securing the balance of power. The 21st century balance of power doesn&amp;rsquo;t depend on weapons, it&amp;rsquo;s increasingly about information. To stay empowered, citizens need an explicit right to:&lt;br /&gt;
		
        
      </description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2013 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <link>www.jasonwillems.com//2013/11/16/21st-Century-Analogue-to-the-Second-Amendment/</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">www.jasonwillems.com//2013/11/16/21st-Century-Analogue-to-the-Second-Amendment/</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apple&#39;s Skeuomorphism U&amp;#8211Turn</title>
      <description>
        
          &lt;h1&gt;Apple&#39;s Skeuomorphism U&amp;#8211Turn&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;br&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;subheading&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div id=&quot;blogdatestamp&quot; style=&quot;font-weight:bold;font-family:times;text-align:center;&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;27 Mar 2013&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div id=&quot;blogtext&quot;&gt;
        Personally, I think the controversy surrounding Skeuomorphism debate feels somewhat synthetic; something the Apple marketing team has been actively trying to stir up. Perhaps not foolishly. Apple has failed to excite for quite some time, and equally worryingly, appears to spend most of its time on the defensive &amp;#8212 a foreign stance to the company since the release of the iPod. The last two years of very incremental updates from Apple, has likely played a significant &amp;#8212 if not dominant &amp;#8212 role in the rise of Google and Microsoft in industries Apple once stood unchallenged.
        &lt;br/&gt;
        &lt;br/&gt;
        With the release of iOS 7 and the manner through which Apple presented it itself at WWDC, it is clear that for better or worse, and after a sustained period of self&amp;#8211doubt, Apple is as aggressive and confident in themselves as they have ever been. Until recently, it was clear Apple employees weren&#39;t stashing Zunes in their pocket, or PCs in their homes, but I imagine some Samsung phones have started making an appearance. Genuine belief in their work can be a very powerful marketing tool, and this is what Apple wants back, and wants to convince its employees as well as its users of. 
        &lt;br/&gt;
        
        
      </description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2013 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <link>www.jasonwillems.com//2013/03/27/Apple-Skeuomorphism-U%E2%80%93Turn/</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">www.jasonwillems.com//2013/03/27/Apple-Skeuomorphism-U%E2%80%93Turn/</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Primer on cURL</title>
      <description>
        
          &lt;h1&gt;A Primer on cURL&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;br&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;subheading&quot;&gt;
	&lt;div id=&quot;blogdatestamp&quot; style=&quot;font-weight:bold;font-family:times;text-align:center;&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;08 Mar 2013&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;div id=&quot;blogtext&quot;&gt;
		I&#39;m updating this post, and it will be back soon!
		
        
      </description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2013 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <link>www.jasonwillems.com//2013/03/08/A-Primer-on-cURL/</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">www.jasonwillems.com//2013/03/08/A-Primer-on-cURL/</guid>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>